A Guide to the Records the Virginia Commission on Youth, 1991-2001
Library of Virginia
- Study documentation records, 1991-2001., Extent: 35 boxes. (Box 1-35)
  - Role of Guardian Ad Litem (GAL) and Courtroom Environment in Child Sexual Assault Cases, 1989-1997.
    - Virginia statutory authority, undated. (Box 9)
    - National models, undated. (Box 9)
    - CASA Programs, 1993. (Box 9)
    - GAL - Testimony, 1993. (Box 9)
    - Self report, undated. (Box 9)
    - Compensation, undated. (Box 9)
    - Children on trial, undated. (Box 9)
    - Ethical considerations, 1993. (Box 9)
    - National Study of GAL Representation, 1990. (Box 9)
    - Pilot evaluation, 1997. (Box 9)
  - Adoption Laws, 1999-2000.
    - Correspondence, 1999-2000. (Box 9)
    - Adoption Law Subcommittee - Meetings, 1999. (Box 9)
    - Policy Manual (DSS), undated. (Box 9)
    - Data, 1999. (Box 9)
    - Work group, 1999-2000. (Box 9)
    - Surveys, 1999. (Box 9)
    - Disclosure / Open records, undated. (Box 9)
    - Uniform Adoption Act, 1995. (Box 9)
    - Adoption and Safe Families Act, 1999. (Box 9)
  - Youth Gangs in Virginia, 1996-1997.
    - Correspondence, 1996. (Box 10a)
    - Executive Summary (HJR 92), 1996. (Box 10a)
    - Miscellaneous, 1996-1997. (Box 10a)
    - National Prevention Stragegy, undated. (Box 10a)
    - Newspaper articles, 1996-1997. (Box 10a)
    - Public hearing / testimony, 1996. (Box 10a)
    - Recommendations, 1996-1997. (Box 10a)
    - Report draft, 1996-1997. (Box 10a)
    - Report draft - Comments, 1996. (Box 10a)
    - Surveys, 1996. (Box 10a)
    - Survey results, 1996. (Box 10a)
    - Workgroup meeting, 1996. (Box 10a)
  - Juvenile Competency Issues in Legal Proceedings, 1996-2000.
    - ABA standards, undated. (Box 10a)
    - Analysis (DJJ), 1996. (Box 10c)
    - Brown's School contract, 1998. (Box 10a)
    - Comments, 1996. (Box 10c)
    - Correspondence, 1998. (Box 10a)
    - Correspondence, 1999. (Box 10a)
    - Cost calculations, undated. (Box 10a)
    - CSU runs and survey, undated. (Box 10c)
    - Data collection, 1996. (Box 10c)
    - Detention analysis, 1996. (Box 10c)
    - Forensic data, undated. (Box 10a)
    - Gang maps, undated. (Box 10c)
    - Juvenile justice and mental health, undated. (Box 10a)
    - Law enforcement, undated. (Box 10c)
    - Law enforcement survey, 1996. (Box 10c)
    - Miscellaneous, undated. (Box 10c)
    - Parent education / competency, undated. (Box 10a)
    - Presentations, 1998-1999. (Box 10a)
    - Requests for proposals, 2000. (Box 10a)
    - State statutes and Supreme Court rulings, undated. (Box 10a)
    - Survey attachments, 1996. (Box 10c)
    - Survey data, 1996. (Box 10c)
    - Survey project, 1996. (Box 10c)
    - Surveys, 1996. (Box 10b)
    - Training Manual - Mental health law of serious juvenile offenders, 1995. (Box 10a)
    - Workgroup meetings, 1998. (Box 10a)
    - Workgroup meetings, 1998. (Box 10c)
    - Workgroup notes and research, 1996. (Box 10c)
  - Feasibility of 10 Year Follow up for Juvenile Sex Offenders, 1993-1994.
    - Juvenile sex offender citations, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Juvenile sexual abuse prevention, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Juvenile sexual abuse treatment, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Report - Mandatory monitoring of juvenile sex offenders for 10 years (HJR 467), 1994. (Box 11)
    - Sexual abuse code citations, undated. (Box 11)
    - Treating the incarcerate male sex offender, undated. (Box 11)
    - Treatment of adult offenders, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Workgroup materials, 1993. (Box 11)
  - Regional Videotaping Centers for Child Sexual Assault Victims, 1998-1999.
    - Closed circuit testimony material (DCJS), 1992-1999. (Box 11)
    - House Document 22, 1999. (Box 11)
    - Resources, undated. (Box 11)
    - Workgroup meetings, 1998. (Box 11)
  - Model Child Custody and Visitation Schedules, 1993-1994.
    - Custody case law, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Custody evaluations and assessors, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Custody investigations, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Custody research, undated. (Box 11)
    - Divorce codes, undated. (Box 11)
    - Divorce education, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Domestic violence issues, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Factors influencing judicial decisions, undated. (Box 11)
    - Final report, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Gender bias studies, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Gender Bias Task Force, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Impact on child support, undated. (Box 11)
    - Joint custody research, undated. (Box 11)
    - Legislation, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Mediation, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Mediation in custody, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Model codes, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Senate Document 96, 1994. (Box 11)
    - Visitation guidelines, 1993. (Box 11)
    - Workgroup records, 1993-1994. (Box 11)
  - Student Discipline Statutes, 2000-2001.
    - Absentee rates, 2000. (Box 12)
    - House Document 32, 2001. (Box 12)
    - Statutes and correspondence, 2000. (Box 12)
    - Truant Officer funding, 2000. (Box 12)
    - Workgroup records, 2000-2001. (Box 12)
  - Standby Guardianship, 1997-1998.
    - Background information, 1997. (Box 12)
    - Correspondence and legislation, 1997-1998. (Box 12)
    - Statutes from other states, 1997. (Box 12)
    - Senate Document 20, 1998. (Box 12)
  - Kinship Care, 2000-2001.
    - Aging, Dept. for the, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Articles, 2000. (Box 13)
    - California - Kinship care, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Contacts, 2000. (Box 13)
    - CWLA literature, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Delaware - Foster care, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Federal literature, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Florida - Kinship care, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Focus group - Big Stone Gap, 2000. (Box 12)
    - Illinois - Kinship care, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Kinship Care - House Document 71, 1994. (Box 13)
    - Kinship Care Project, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Louisiana - Kinship care, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Maryland - Kinship care, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Massachusettes - Kinship care, 2000. (Box 13)
    - New York - Kinship care, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Oregon - Kinship care, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Private funding for foster care, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Senate Document 23, 2001. (Box 12)
    - SJR 208 Overview, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Study, 2001. (Box 13)
    - Survey, 2000. (Box 12)
    - Survey - Local agency feedback, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Survey - Results, 2000. (Box 13)
    - Wisconsin - Kinship care, 2000. (Box 13)
  - Alternative Education, 1999-2000.
    - Court Service Unit surveys of the educational needs of court involved students, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Alternative education information, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Coy data findings, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Cities) - Alexandria, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Bristol, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Buena Vista, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Charlottesville, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Chesapeake, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Colonial Beach, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Colonial Heights, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Covington, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Danville, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Falls Church, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Franklin, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Fredericksburg, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Hampton, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Hopewell, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Lexington, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Lynchburg, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Manassas, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Manassas Park, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Martinsville, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Newport News, 1999-2000. (Box 14c)
    - Localities (Cities) - Norfolk, 1999-2000. (Box 14c)
    - Localities (Cities) - Virginia Beach, 1999-2000. (Box 14c)
    - Localities (Cities) - Norton, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Petersburg, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Poquoson, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Radford, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Richmond, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Roanoke, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Staunton, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Suffolk, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Waynesboro, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - West Point, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Cities) - Winchester, 1999-2000. (Box 14a)
    - Localities (Counties) - Accomack, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Alleghany, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Amelia, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Amherst, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Arlington, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Augsust, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Bath, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Bedford, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Bland, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Botetourt, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Brunswick, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Buchanan, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Buckingham, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Campbell, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Caroline, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Carroll, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Charles City, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Charlotte, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Chesterfield, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Clarke, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Craig, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Culpeper, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Cumberland, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Dickenson, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Dinwiddie, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Essex, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Fairfax, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Fauquier, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Floyd, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Fluvanna, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Franklin, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Frederick, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Giles, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Gloucester, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Goochland, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Grayson, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Greene, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Greensville, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Halifax, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Hanover, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Henrico, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Highland, 1999-2000. (Box 14b)
    - Localities (Counties) - Isle of Wight, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - James City, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - King and Queen, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - King George, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - King William, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Lancaster, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Lee, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Loudoun, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Louisa, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Lunenburg, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Madison, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Mathews, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Mecklenburg, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Middlesex, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Montgomery, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Nelson, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - New Kent, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Northampton, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Northumberland, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Nottoway, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Orange, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Page, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Patrick, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Pittsylvania, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Powhatan, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Prince Edward, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Prince George, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Prince William, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Pulaski, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Rappahannock, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Richmond, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Roanoke City, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Rockbridge, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Rockingham, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Russell, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Scott, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Shenandoah, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Smyth, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Southampton, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Spotsylvania, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Stafford, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Surry, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Sussex, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Tazewell, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Warren, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Washington, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Westmoreland, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Wise, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - Wythe, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
    - Localities (Counties) - York, 1999-2000. (Box 14d)
  - Youth with Serious Emotional Disturbance Requiring Out-of-Home Treatment, 2000-2001.
    - Correspondence, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Correspondence, 2000-2001. (Box 15c)
    - Meeting records, 2000-2001. (Box 15c)
    - Research material, 2000-2001. (Box 15c)
    - Treatment modalities, 2000-2001. (Box 15c)
    - Surveys - Accomack, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Albemarle, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Appomattox, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)
    - Surveys - Arlington, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Buckingham, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)
    - Surveys - Campbell, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)
    - Surveys - Chesterfield, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)
    - Surveys - Dinwiddie, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)
    - Surveys - Fairfax, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Floyd, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Fredericksburg, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Grayson, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Hampton, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Lynchburg, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)
    - Surveys - Martinsville, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Montgomery, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)
    - Surveys - Norfolk, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Richmond City, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)
    - Surveys - Roanoke, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Southampton, 2000-2001. (Box 15a)
    - Surveys - Staunton, 2000-2001. (Box 15c)
    - Surveys - Westmoreland, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)
    - Surveys - Wythe, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)
    - Surveys - York, 2000-2001. (Box 15b)